Jorge Moller

Senior Front-end Developer

Senior front-end developer based in Uruguay. I have been working in the IT industry for the past 7 years now and have an extensive experience in both technical and business related. I would describe myself as a self-motivated worker, agile learner and proactive person who is always trying to learn and improve with the purpose of contributing something new to my colleagues.

Personal Details

• Full name: Jorge Andrés Moller Escobar

• Date and place of birth: 21 June 1989, Montevideo

Address: Nancy 4415 - Buceo, Montevideo

• Cell phone: +598 099 52 04 52

• Email: jmoller2106@gmail.com

Skype: jmoller2106

Skills

• HTML

SASS / CSS / BEM

JavaScript (ES6)

Flow

React JS:

- Redux

- Redux Form

- Redux Sagas - Styled Components• TDD (test driven development)

- Enzyme

- Jest

Express (REST API)

mongoDB

Illustrator

Photoshop

Sketch

Professional Career

Self-employed 2016 - present

Senior front-end developer

I am working as a senior front-end developer for personal clients in Uruguay. My main focus is to build corporate websites and web applications. Over the past few years I developed an e-commerce solution for one of my clients, I was in charge of the design and development process for the entire application using React JS with Redux for the front-end, and Express with mongoDB for the back-end. I also worked designing and building several corporate websites, using illustrator for pixel perfect illustrations, sketch for rapid prototyping and SASS, BEM, HTML and JavaScript in the development stage. I also took up a side project building a full administrator template using SASS, BEM and Javascript (ES6).

Technologies and tools used:

React JSTDD

Illustrator

Kanban

SASS / BEM

Express

Photoshop

JavaScript (ES6)

mongoDB

Sketch

Integra CCS 2014 - 2016

Front-end Developer

As a front-end developer me and my team were responsible for the production, modification and maintenance of uContact, an all in one call center web application. To do so, we used HTML5 (web RTC, web sockets, web workers, audio API, drag and drop, desktop notifications, client side storage), CSS, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, Javascript and jQuery.

As far as project management goes, we worked with Atlassian software development and collaboration suite which includes: Bitbucket for source code management, Jira and Jira Agile (Kanban) for issue tracking, Git and Source Tree for version control and IDE respectively, Hip Chat for team collaboration, Confluence for documentation and Bamboo for running builds and test.

Technologies and tools used:

- HTML 5 (web RTC, web sockets, web workers, audio API, drag and drop, desktop notifications, client side storage)
- · CSS, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, Javascript and jQuery.

Bookingforce 2013 - 2014

ASP.NET Developer

I was responsible for development and maintenance of a digital marketing and booking engine system for hotels. Among my tasks was: developing new features, bug fixes, client support and web design. To do so I worked with a variety of technologies from front-end, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, to server-side, C#, ASP.NET, including SQL Server 2008 as data store and LINQ.

Technologies and tools used:

- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- LINQ and SQL Server 2008
- C# and ASP.NET

TATA Consultancy Services 2011 - 2013

IT Support Specialist

Worked as an IT support specialist providing technical support for TARGET, the second-largest department store retailer in the United States. I was in charge of collecting feedback from the pharmacist department, providing a rapid solution or workaround to their problems.

Self-motivated to develop different automation tools to improve processes and enhance support, such as a monitoring software that retrieved the prescriptions that took longer by the server to process. The time it took us to do that particular task went down from 15 minutes to 30 seconds.

Technologies and tools used:

- C#, ADO.NET, SQL Server 2008
- Web Services
- ADO.NET, Windows Forms.

Education

La Mennais Elementary School 1996 - 2001

La Mennais HighSchool 2001 - 2007

FCE: First Certificate in English 1996 - 2006

From 1996 to 2006 studied english at Dickens Institute.

ORT University 2008 - 2013

Career path: science computer engineering